Sometimes life doesn’t seem to play fair.
有时候生活似乎并不公平。
It blindsides you at the most inopportune moments, and even if we can learn to grin and bear the ups and downs, they can take their toll on our psyche.
它总在最不合时宜的时刻出其不意地打击我们，即便我们能学默默承受人生的起起落落，这些经历也会对我们的心理造成伤害。
So rather than suffer in silence or let these things get you down, maybe there is another way: what if humour can help you get through the dark times?
所以，与其默默承受痛苦，或是任由这些事情击垮自己，或许还有另一种办法：用幽默来帮你度过低谷期会怎么样呢？
According to author and clinician Kristen Lee: “Laughter and tears are both therapeutic – we need both to process such hard times.”
作家兼临床医师克里斯汀·李表示：“欢笑与泪水都具有治愈功能——面对艰难时刻，我们需要二者兼备才能消化那些情绪。”
But how can we find the tough things that happen funny?
但我们该如何从糟糕的事情中找到笑点呢？
Our lives are really serious, often filled with mundane and repetitive activities, whether it’s arbitrary bill paying or fighting for a seat on your commute, we need to make time for fun and play – enjoy the little things.
生活本就十分严肃，还常常充斥着单调重复的琐事，无论是毫无理由地付账单，还是通勤时抢座位，我们都需要挤出时间自娱自乐——享受生活中的小确幸。
Why not make funny noises to remind you to stop taking things seriously, or learn some silly jokes, just to tell when times get hard?
不妨试着弄出些搞怪的声响来提醒自己别把一切都看得太严肃，或者学几个无聊的笑话，专门在境遇不顺的时候讲出来。
They could make you or other people around you laugh!
这些小举动说不定能让你自己，或是身边的人开怀一笑！
When a hurdle pops up in life, it’s easy to get bogged down – but the way we recount events can impact on our resilience.
当生活中出现难关时，人很容易陷入困顿——但我们讲述经历的方式，会影响自身的心理韧性。
Rather than see the negatives, look for the ironic moments and tell people about them!
与其只盯着消极的一面，不如去发掘那些充满讽刺意味的瞬间，讲给别人听！
Why not write parodies in your spare time about events that take place to help you compartmentalise?
闲暇时，何不为发生过的事情写一些戏仿作品，帮助自己梳理情绪呢？
Script what happened as if it was happening to a character rather than yourself.
把所经历的事情写成剧本，就当这些事发生在某个角色身上，而非你自己。
We all know that some things in life aren’t fair.
我们都知道，生活中有些事本就不公平。
But take those events and send them up a bit in your scripts!
但不妨把这些事写进剧本里调侃一番！
Sometimes life needs a bit of a roasting to get your thoughts in order, and embracing your comedic side, seeing life’s difficult moments as obstacles that can be made fun of rather than overwhelm you, may help you get through them more easily.
有时候，生活需要被“吐槽”一番，才能理清思绪。展现自己幽默的一面，把生活中的困境看作可以拿来打趣的障碍，而非压垮自己的重担，或许能让你更轻松地度过难关。
And who knows, you may just discover a talent for writing at the end of it.
谁知道呢，说不定最后你还能发掘出自己的写作天赋呢。